(The drama was based on a book, and all people, organizations,)
(이 드라마는 책을 원작으로 하였으며, 모든 사람, 조직,
(locations, and incidents in this drama are fictitious.)
(본 드라마의 장소와 사건은 허구입니다.)
(It was filmed in accordance with COVID-19 prevention guidelines.)
(코로나19 예방수칙에 따라 촬영되었습니다.)
Whatever the case, more heinous criminals will show up.
어떤 경우이든 더 흉악한 범죄자들이 나타날 것입니다.
This team is always working very hard.
이 팀은 항상 열심히 일하고 있습니다.
But there still has to be someone preparing for what may happen.
그러나 일어날 수 있는 일에 대비하는 사람은 여전히 ​​있어야 합니다.
I need you to take up a case.
당신이 사건을 맡아주셨으면 합니다.
A married couple was murdered in their home two weeks ago.
2주 전 한 부부가 자신의 집에서 살해당했습니다.
There was cash lying around, but he didn't even touch it.
주변에 현금이 있었지만 그는 손도 대지 않았습니다.
They think it's an act of resentment masked as a burglary.
그들은 그것이 강도로 가면을 쓴 원한 행위라고 생각합니다.
It's clean.
깨끗해요.
It means the victims were overpowered...
피해자들이 압도당했다는 뜻인데...
without any sort of resistance.
어떤 저항도 없이.
(Gungok-dong Family Murder Case, September 24, 2003)
(군곡동 일가족 살인사건, 2003년 9월 24일)
A type of systematic crime committed according to a plan.
계획에 따라 저질러지는 조직범죄의 일종.
Is this a way of expressing...
표현방식인가...
the culprit's emotions caused by a grudge they hold?
범인의 원한으로 인한 감정?
They are both hiking shoes.
둘 다 등산화입니다.
This one is from Suseong-dong, Gangnam.
강남 수성동에서 온 제품입니다.
And this one is from Gungok-dong, Jongno.
그리고 이건 종로 군곡동에서 나온 거예요.
They are from different districts, but it's the same culprit?
서로 다른 지역 출신인데 범인은 같다?
(Jinjung-dong, Gangnam-gu)
(강남구 진중동)
There was another case in Jinjung-dong.
진주동에서는 또 다른 사건이 있었습니다.
You're not an investigator. Why are you here?
당신은 조사관이 아닙니다. 당신은 왜 여기에 있습니까?
Please. I must check the crime scene.
제발. 범죄 현장을 확인해야 해요.
Hey. Didn't you hear me? I told you to get lost, you punk!
여기요. 내 말 못 들었어? 내가 길을 잃으라고 했잖아, 이 새끼야!
Darn it.
젠장.
This is important.
이것은 중요합니다.
The victim was hit by a blunt instrument.
피해자는 둔기에 맞았습니다.
And the safe wasn't touched either.
그리고 금고도 건드리지 않았습니다.
This is the third murder, and his only purpose is...
이번이 세 번째 살인이고, 그의 유일한 목적은...
to kill.
죽이다.
It's a serial murder.
연쇄 살인입니다.
(Hwanghwa-dong, Jongno-gu)
(종로구 황화동)
Hurry to the scene in Hwanghwa-dong.
서둘러 황화동 현장으로 달려가세요.
A senior citizen was murdered.
한 노인이 살해당했습니다.
Why did he suddenly start a fire?
왜 갑자기 불을 지른 걸까요?
He tried doing something he had never done before.
그는 이전에 한 번도 해본 적이 없는 일을 시도했습니다.
I'm sure he came across an unexpected situation.
나는 그가 예상치 못한 상황에 직면했다고 확신합니다.
He either wanted to destroy traces he didn't want anyone to see.
그는 누구에게도 보여주고 싶지 않은 흔적을 없애고 싶었습니다.
Or it could've been his trace.
아니면 그의 흔적이었을 수도 있습니다.
I mean the CCTV footage.
CCTV 영상을 말하는데요.
We got a shot of the back of the culprit.
범인의 뒷모습을 촬영했습니다.
Let's put out an APB.
APB를 내보내자.
You want us to do that with just the footage that shows his back?
그의 등이 보이는 영상만으로 그렇게 하길 원하시나요?
Are you suggesting that we give him a warning...
우리가 그에게 경고를 하라고 제안하는 겁니까?
- that he could get caught? - That's correct.
- 잡힐 수도 있다고요? - 맞습니다.
The only way to stop him from striking again...
그가 다시 공격하는 것을 막을 수 있는 유일한 방법은...
is this.
이것이다.
The footage shows a man walking. He's wearing a black jacket.
영상에는 한 남자가 걷고 있는 모습이 담겨 있다. 그는 검은색 재킷을 입고 있어요.
The police have identified this man in the footage...
경찰은 영상에서 이 남성의 신원을 확인했습니다.
Even after you let out the APB...
APB를 내보낸 뒤에도...
At least share the information with me!
최소한 나에게 정보를 공유해주세요!
It's been over three months...
3개월이 넘었는데..
and the police still don't have a single lead on the culprit.
경찰은 아직도 범인에 대한 단서를 하나도 갖고 있지 않습니다.
The decision for an open search.
공개 검색에 대한 결정입니다.
Is this the police's lifeline?
이게 경찰의 생명줄인가요?
Or is this the beginning of doom?
아니면 이것이 파멸의 시작인가?
Did he give up on committing another crime to hide?
숨기기 위해 또 다른 범죄를 포기한 걸까?
Or is he still planning another crime?
아니면 아직도 또 다른 범죄를 계획하고 있는 걸까요?
You never miss a day.
하루도 놓치지 마세요.
We never know when the crimes will start again.
범죄는 언제 다시 시작될지 알 수 없습니다.
We will catch him. Certainly.
우리는 그를 잡을 것입니다. 틀림없이.
What if the culprit changed the MO?
범인이 MO를 바꾸었다면?
What do we do then?
그러면 우리는 무엇을 합니까?
- Gosh, what are the police doing? - Right.
- 이런, 경찰은 뭐하는 거야? - 오른쪽.
They still haven't been able to catch a punk like this.
그들은 아직 이런 놈을 잡지 못했습니다.
- I know right? - Yes.
- 나도 알아요? - 예.
(Attacked with a camping knife.)
(캠핑칼로 공격한다.)
(Sinheung 2-dong, Yeongdeungpo-gu)
(영등포구 신흥2동)
(February 12, 2004)
(2004년 2월 12일)
(Through the Darkness, Part 2)
(어둠을 뚫고 2부)
(Episode 7)
(7화)
(Booyoung Station, Exit 7)
(부영역 7번출구)
(Milk)
(우유)
(Reward 50,000 Dollars, Seoul Metropolitan Police Agency)
(포상금 5만달러, 서울지방경찰청)
(Daily Case Report, February 12)
(일일 사례 보고, 2월 12일)
(Daily Case Report)
(일일 사례보고)
(Victim Park So Eun, Age 22, Female)
(피해자 박소은, 22세, 여)
(On February 12, 2004, the victim was stabbed...)
(2004년 2월 12일 피해자가 칼에 찔림..)
(in the chest, stomach, and side on her way home.)
(집으로 가는 길에 가슴, 배, 옆구리에.)
- It's so cold. - It's warm inside.
- 너무 추워요. - 안은 따뜻해요.
- You're early. - You're here.
- 일찍 왔군요. - 여기 있어요.
You got here so early.
당신은 여기에 너무 일찍 도착했습니다.
- Yes, I came in early. - It's freezing.
- 네, 일찍 들어왔어요. - 추워요.
- It's really cold out, isn't it? - Yes.
- 정말 춥지 않나요? - 예.
Inspector Song.
송 검사님.
Last week, I made a wish while looking at the first full moon...
지난주 첫 보름달을 보며 소원을 빌었는데..
of the year.
올해의.
What?
무엇?
You see, it's been four years since I joined the team.
그러고 보니 제가 팀에 합류한 지 벌써 4년이 됐습니다.
I really hope you can start...
정말 시작할 수 있기를 바랍니다...
talking to me casually this year.
올해는 나에게 아무렇지도 않게 말을 걸었다.
Hey, you're too much. It's been four years.
이봐, 넌 너무 과해 4년이 지났습니다.
Woo Ju says it's his wish.
우주는 자신의 소원이라고 말한다.
Woo Ju, our universe! Can't you just grant his wish?
우주야, 우리 우주! 그 사람의 소원을 들어줄 수는 없나요?
Was that a joke?
농담이었나요?
I'll start talking casually from now on.
지금부터 담담하게 이야기를 시작하겠습니다.
Really?
정말?
Gosh. Had I known it'd be this easy, I would've brought it up long ago.
이런. 이렇게 쉬울 줄 알았더라면 진작에 꺼냈을 텐데.
Had I known it'd be this easy, I would've done it long ago.
이렇게 쉬울 줄 알았더라면 진작에 해봤을 텐데.
I took too long, didn't I?
너무 오래 걸렸지, 그렇지?
Are you playing favorites?
좋아하는 게임을 하고 있나요?
You never laugh when I tell jokes.
내가 농담을 할 때 당신은 결코 웃지 않습니다.
That wasn't funny at all, but you laughed.
전혀 웃기지 않았는데 웃으셨어요.
He laughed because he likes me, not because I'm funny.
그 사람은 내가 웃겨서가 아니라 나를 좋아해서 웃었다.
That's right.
좋아요.
Hey, what's with you guys this morning?
오늘 아침에 너희들 무슨 일 있어?
You're so mean.
당신은 정말 못됐어요.
Anything showing a similar pattern?
비슷한 패턴을 보이는 것이 있나요?
- No, nothing with the same pattern. - Let's see.
- 아니요, 같은 패턴은 없습니다. - 어디 보자.
(Daily Case Report)
(일일 사례보고)
An assault case...
폭행사건..
Nothing.
아무것도.
I hope he has stopped.
그가 멈추기를 바랍니다.
(Thursday, February 12)
(2월 12일 목요일)
Whatever he may be doing,
그 사람이 무엇을 하든,
let's just stay focused and keep going.
그냥 집중하고 계속 가자.
We got this.
우리는 이것을 얻었습니다.
(Profiling Report)
(프로파일링 보고서)
Why are you going through the profiling report?
프로파일링 보고서를 검토하는 이유는 무엇인가요?
Hoping to find some clues.
몇 가지 단서를 찾기를 바랍니다.
Clues, my foot.
단서, 내 발.
Because we listened to that idiot, Song Ha Young,
그 바보 송하영 말을 들었으니까.
the entire police force was criticized for being incompetent.
경찰 전체가 무능하다는 비판을 받았다.
And now, the culprit has gone into hiding.
그리고 이제 범인은 숨어들었습니다.
Where are you going?
어디 가세요?
Why do you care?
왜 신경쓰나요?
Oh, it's a record.
아, 기록이군요.
He got here less than 30 minutes ago.
그는 여기에 온 지 30분도 채 안 됐어요.
(Hwanghwa-dong Murder)
(황화동 살인사건)
(Victim Yoon Jung Yoon, Age 65, Female)
(피해자 윤정윤, 65세, 여)
The clock's ticking, but we have no idea...
시계는 똑딱거리고 있지만 우리는 전혀 모릅니다...
where this scum is.
이 쓰레기는 어디에 있습니까?
- Oh, you're early. - Hello.
- 아, 일찍 왔구나. - 안녕하세요.
- You're early too. - How have you been?
- 너도 일찍 왔구나. - 잘 지냈어요?
Woo Ju, say hello before you step out.
우주야, 나가기 전에 인사 좀 해라.
Nice to meet you.
만나서 반가워요.
This case made me feel the need to study,
이 사건을 계기로 공부의 필요성을 느꼈고,
so I'll be joining you today.
그래서 오늘은 함께하겠습니다.
Good thinking.
좋은 생각입니다.
- I'll be right back. - Okay, hurry.
- 금방 돌아올게요. - 알았어, 서둘러.
We'll get started when Woo Ju is back.
우주가 돌아오면 시작하겠습니다.
- Take a seat. - You can sit here.
- 자리에 앉으세요. - 여기 앉으시면 됩니다.
Professors.
교수.
There are so many scumbags in this world...
세상에는 쓰레기가 너무 많아요...
that we've got lots of studying to do.
우리가 공부할 게 너무 많다는 걸요.
About the serial murders of affluent senior citizens.
부유층 노인 연쇄살인 사건에 대해.
You haven't identified the murder weapon yet, have you?
아직 살인 무기를 확인하지 못하셨나요?
No, not yet.
아니요, 아직은 아닙니다.
What causes that triangle-shaped scar?
저 삼각형 모양의 흉터는 왜 생기는 걸까요?
We've been checking every blunt weapon we can think of,
우리는 우리가 생각할 수 있는 모든 둔기 무기를 검사해 왔습니다.
but haven't found a match so far.
하지만 지금까지 일치하는 항목을 찾지 못했습니다.
The abrasion, hypodermal bleeding, and laceration.
찰과상, 피하 출혈 및 열상.
Also considering the depth of the dent,
찌그러짐의 깊이도 고려하여,
it's not a light weapon.
가벼운 무기가 아닙니다.
Considering the weight and force applied,
가해지는 무게와 힘을 고려하면,
a steel hammer would be a match,
강철 망치가 성냥이 될 것입니다.
but they're usually either round or sharp.
하지만 일반적으로 둥글거나 날카롭습니다.
And the handle is long, so it'll be a hassle to carry it around.
그리고 손잡이가 길어서 들고다니기 불편할 것 같아요.
Captain Kook, I'm beginning to think that your guess may be correct.
국 선장님, 당신의 추측이 맞을지도 모른다는 생각이 들기 시작했습니다.
It makes me feel uneasy.
그것은 나를 불안하게 만든다.
That the culprit made the weapon himself?
범인이 직접 무기를 만들었다고?
If it really is the case, we won't be able to identify it.
만약 그렇다면, 우리는 그것을 식별할 수 없을 것입니다.
I've never seen anyone put so much effort into murders.
나는 누군가가 살인에 그렇게 많은 노력을 기울이는 것을 본 적이 없습니다.
- Let's go. - Gosh, it's so cold.
- 갑시다. - 맙소사, 너무 추워요.
Anyway, is the lady in that building okay?
그나저나 저 건물 아줌마 괜찮아요?
- I think so. - My goodness.
- 그렇게 생각해요. - 맙소사.
- What if she died... - That building.
- 만약 죽으면 어쩌지... - 저 건물.
- Gosh. - My goodness.
- 이런. - 맙소사.
What happened in that building?
그 건물에서 무슨 일이 일어났나요?
Last night, a lady on the second floor nearly died.
어젯밤 2층에 있던 아주머니가 죽을 뻔했어요.
Thank goodness she didn't die.
다행스럽게도 그녀는 죽지 않았습니다.
A stranger followed her and stabbed her. My gosh.
낯선 사람이 그녀를 따라와 그녀를 찔렀습니다. 맙소사.
She didn't die?
그녀는 죽지 않았나요?
She's still alive?
아직 살아 있나요?
Richard Chase was also abused by his parents as a kid.
Richard Chase도 어렸을 때 부모님에게 학대를 받았습니다.
He experienced bed-wetting,
그는 야뇨증을 경험했고,
committed arson, and animal abuse,
방화, 동물학대 등을 저질렀다.
which are common characteristics of serial killers.
연쇄살인범의 공통적인 특징이죠.
He killed adults and children...
그는 어른과 아이들을 죽였습니다 ...
in a brutal manner.
잔인하게.
He didn't have hostile relationships with the victims.
그는 피해자들과 적대적인 관계를 맺지 않았습니다.
Why did he brutally murder victims chosen at random?
그는 왜 무작위로 선택된 피해자들을 잔인하게 살해했을까?
Most murderers like him kill for pleasure.
그와 같은 대부분의 살인자는 즐거움을 위해 살인합니다.
For pleasure, not because of anger?
분노 때문이 아니라 즐거움 때문에?
That is the most frightening part.
그것이 가장 무서운 부분이다.
It means killing makes them happy.
그것은 살인이 그들을 행복하게 만든다는 것을 의미합니다.
Killing satisfies them,
죽이는 것이 그들을 만족시키고,
so they can't stop.
그래서 그들은 멈출 수 없습니다.
They actually become bolder, looking for bigger pleasures.
그들은 실제로 더 대담해지고 더 큰 즐거움을 찾습니다.
- Correct. - That's why he mutilated...
- 옳은. - 그래서 그가 절단을 한 거야...
and even cannibalized his victims.
심지어 희생자들을 잡아먹기도 했습니다.
Sexually deviant killers tend to commit such acts.
성적으로 일탈적인 살인범은 그러한 행위를 저지르는 경향이 있습니다.
So Richard Chase's cases are often categorized as lust murders...
그래서 Richard Chase의 사건은 종종 정욕 살인으로 분류됩니다.
and as sexual homicides.
그리고 성적인 살인자로.
Sexual homicides?
성살인?
That's right.
좋아요.
The way he mutilated his victims doesn't show a specific pattern.
그가 피해자를 절단한 방식은 특정한 패턴을 보여주지 않습니다.
There's no pattern at all.
전혀 패턴이 없습니다.
He didn't know much about human anatomy,
그는 인체 해부학에 대해 아는 바가 별로 없었습니다.
nor did he try to study.
그는 공부하려고도 하지 않았습니다.
Right, and he didn't even bother tidying up the scene.
그렇죠, 그리고 그는 현장 정리에도 신경 쓰지 않았습니다.
He didn't even try to conceal evidence.
증거를 은폐하려는 노력도 하지 않았다.
So we could say that Chase's murders were unsystematic.
따라서 체이스의 살인은 체계적이지 못했다고 말할 수 있습니다.
He chose his victims at random, and it wasn't premeditated.
그는 희생자를 무작위로 선택했고, 그것은 계획된 것이 아니었습니다.
And even when he was caught at the scene,
그리고 현장에서 잡혔을 때도
he was very confused.
그는 매우 혼란스러워했습니다.
On top of that, he suffered from schizophrenia.
게다가 그는 정신분열증을 앓았다.
His cases were typical unsystematic murders.
그의 사건은 전형적인 비체계적 살인이었다.
We need a list of your psychiatric patients...
정신질환자 명단이 필요해요...
from the past 5 years, dating back to 1999.
1999년부터 지난 5년간.
Don't you feel all cooped up being stuck in the press room?
기자실에 갇힌 것 같지 않나요?
You're still doing field coverage and writing all the articles.
당신은 여전히 ​​현장 취재를 하고 있으며 모든 기사를 쓰고 있습니다.
I commend you for your enthusiasm, but your juniors will hate you.
나는 당신의 열정을 칭찬하지만 후배들은 당신을 싫어할 것입니다.
Aren't we both used to people hating us?
우리 둘 다 사람들이 우리를 미워하는 데 익숙하지 않나요?
Don't you worry.
걱정하지 마세요.
Not me.
나는 아니다.
What are you talking about? Your juniors hate you way more.
무슨 얘기를 하는 건가요? 후배들이 당신을 더 싫어해요.
So?
그래서?
Are you going to do it for me or not?
나를 위해 그 일을 해줄 건가요, 안 해줄 건가요?
We have to catch the serial killer.
연쇄살인범을 잡아야 합니다.
You know that the Special Crime Squad is busy.
특수수사대가 바쁘다는 건 아시죠?
Come on. Don't be like this.
어서 해봐요. 이러지 마세요.
Of course, Mr. Kwak knows how busy you are.
물론 곽씨도 당신이 얼마나 바쁜지 알고 있다.
He keeps filing a report every time his girls go missing,
그는 딸들이 실종될 때마다 계속해서 신고서를 제출하고,
but the police don't seem to care,
하지만 경찰은 별로 신경쓰지 않는 것 같아요.
so he's getting all anxious.
그래서 그는 점점 불안해지고 있어요.
Good grief.
좋은 슬픔.
Hey, over here!
이봐, 여기야!
He's here.
그는 여기 있습니다.
This is the detective. Say hello.
이 형사입니다. 인사하세요.
Reporter Im told me a lot about you.
임 기자가 당신에 대해 많은 이야기를 해줬어요.
Hello, Chief Kim.
안녕하세요, 김 실장님.
I'm Kwak Man Hyun.
저는 곽만현입니다.
(Mr. Kwak in Mapo, Girls in their 20s)
(마포 곽씨, 20대 여학생)
You didn't have to introduce him to me.
그 사람을 나한테 소개할 필요는 없었어요.
Come on. You two should meet.
어서 해봐요. 너희 둘은 만나야 해.
- No pressure. - Yes.
- 압박감은 없어요. - 예.
In any case, pretend not to know me when you run into me at police HQ.
아무튼 경찰서에서 저랑 마주치면 모른 척 해주세요.
I always do. Are you worried I'd suddenly say hi to you?
나는 항상 그렇습니다. 내가 갑자기 인사할까 봐 걱정돼?
Who knows?
누가 알겠어요?
The one thing I learned while working as a detective...
탐정 일을 하면서 배운 것 중 하나..
is that you should never trust anyone.
누구도 절대로 믿어서는 안된다는 것입니다.
- What brings you by? - Hello, sir.
- 무슨 일로 왔나요? - 안녕하세요, 선생님.
This is my first time back here after the team was formed,
팀 결성 후 처음으로 이곳에 왔는데,
and this office still looks crummy.
그런데 이 사무실은 아직도 형편없어 보여요.
Hey, do you have water?
아, 물 있어요?
- Water? - Forget it.
- 물? - 잊어버려요.
Shouldn't you at least be able to tell...
적어도 말은 할 수 있어야 하지 않겠습니까...
whether it's a killer's hideout...
살인자의 은신처인지...
or a place for catching killers?
아니면 살인자를 잡는 곳인가요?
Why are you already trying to pick a fight?
왜 벌써 싸움을 걸려고 하는 거야?
Hey, those red marks. What are they about?
아, 저 빨간 표시. 그들은 무엇에 관한 것입니까?
Today is the 154th day after the 1st case broke out.
오늘은 1차 사건이 발생한 지 154일째 되는 날이다.
And the 105th day after we put out the APB on him.
그리고 APB를 발표한 지 105일째 되는 날이었습니다.
Do you guys even remember your families' birthdays?
여러분, 가족들의 생일도 기억하시나요?
If you're going to tell us to drop it, just leave.
버리라고 할 거면 그냥 나가세요.
Must you kick me out already?
벌써 나를 쫓아내야 하는 건가요?
Why else would the chief of the Special Crime Squad be here?
특수범죄수사대장이 왜 여기에 있겠습니까?
Goodness. Are you a psychic or what?
선량. 당신은 심령술사인가요?
A scary wolf is roaming around inside the rabbit burrow.
토끼굴 안에는 무서운 늑대가 돌아다니고 있어요.
We won't stop until we catch the wolf. End of discussion.
우리는 늑대를 잡을 때까지 멈추지 않을 것입니다. 토론을 종료합니다.
Goodness. Okay, I heard you.
선량. 알았어, 들었어.
Just be careful and stay out of Bong Sik...
그냥 조심해서 봉식씨한테는 접근하지 마세요...
and Captain Yoon's sight.
그리고 윤선장의 모습.
You're the chief of the Special Crime Squad.
당신은 특수범죄수사대의 수장입니다.
Why do you always walk on eggshells around them?
왜 항상 그들 주변의 달걀 껍질 위를 걷는 걸까요?
What? Do you not walk on eggshells around your juniors?
무엇? 후배들 주변에서 달걀껍질 위를 걷지 않나요?
A little bit.
조금.
Captain Yoon is one thing,
윤 선장은 한 가지,
but Bong Sik has such a nasty temper.
그런데 봉식 씨는 성격이 너무 심해요.
I do too.
나도 그래.
What do you say? Should I go ahead and load my gun?
당신은 무엇을 말합니까? 가서 총을 장전해야 할까요?
That lunatic will actually pull the trigger. That's the problem.
그 미치광이는 실제로 방아쇠를 당길 것입니다. 그게 문제입니다.
He's been on everyone's case with that temper of his.
그는 그 성격으로 모든 사람의 문제를 해결해 왔습니다.
Still, we can't just sit back and do nothing.
그렇다고 우리가 가만히 앉아서 아무것도 할 수는 없습니다.
We don't know when the culprit will kill again.
범인이 언제 또 살인을 저지를지 알 수 없다.
It's not like I don't know that! Goodness.
내가 그런 걸 모르는 건 아니잖아! 선량.
My head hurts.
머리가 아프다.
I'm leaving. This place is giving me a headache again.
나는 떠난다. 이 곳이 또 머리를 아프게 하네요.
Would you like a cup of tea...
차 한잔 드실래요...?
Why couldn't you ask sooner?
왜 더 빨리 물어보지 못했나요?
Why are you getting mad at that perfectly nice kid?
그 완벽하게 착한 애한테 왜 화를 내는 거야?
Goodness, taking your teammate's side?
맙소사, 팀원의 편을 들어주시나요?
Be good. I'm watching you.
잘 지내세요. 나는 당신을 지켜보고 있습니다.
Goodbye.
안녕히 가세요.
So why were you really here?
그럼 당신은 정말로 왜 여기 있었나요?
I came because I missed you. Happy?
당신이 그리워서 왔습니다. 행복하다?
Goodbye.
안녕히 가세요.
I'm sure you were here to nag me!
분명 나한테 잔소리 하려고 온 거야!
(Behavioral Analysis Team)
(행동분석팀)
A hundred and five days?
150일?
Goodness, those stubborn wackos.
맙소사, 저 고집 센 괴짜들.
(Police)
(경찰)
Hello.
안녕하세요.
Yoon Tae Gu of Seoul Metropolitan Police Agency.
서울지방경찰청 윤태구 경찰청장.
- I heard you had information. - Yes, I called.
- 정보가 있다고 들었어요. - 네, 전화했어요.
(Nokdangwon)
(녹당원)
I think it's that guy.
내 생각엔 그 사람인 것 같아.
Hey!
여기요!
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
What's with you?
당신은 무엇입니까?
We're detectives of Seoul Metropolitan Police Agency.
저희는 서울지방경찰청 형사들입니다.
Is that so?
그렇습니까?
- I'm sorry. - Okay, fine.
- 죄송합니다. - 알았어, 알았어.
Darn it.
젠장.
The train is approaching.
기차가 다가오고 있습니다.
Please step behind the safety line.
안전선 뒤로 물러나주세요.
Do you think we live with pointless anxiety?
우리가 쓸데없는 불안 속에 살고 있다고 생각하시나요?
It's a habit that comes with the career.
그것은 직업과 함께 오는 습관입니다.
(Han Jong Yong, Yoon Jung Yoon)
(한종용, 윤정윤)
- Gosh, it's pouring. - It's cold.
- 맙소사, 비가 쏟아지네요. - 추워요.
- Hello. - Hello.
- 안녕하세요. - 안녕하세요.
- Are you two coming in? - Yes.
- 둘이 들어오나요? - 예.
- Are you going out? - To the marketplace.
- 나갈 거야? - 시장으로.
Look what you've got there.
거기에 뭐가 있는지 보세요.
(Korean Beef Gopchang)
(한우곱창)
This is really good.
정말 좋습니다.
- Anyway. - Yes?
- 그래도. - 예?
"Is this the police's lifeline or is this the beginning of doom?"
"이것이 경찰의 생명선인가, 아니면 파멸의 시작인가?"
That article was really harsh.
그 글은 정말 가혹했어요.
Why? It's true. What about it?
왜? 사실이에요. 그것은 어떻습니까?
Inspector Song won't show it,
송 경위는 보여주지 않을 거예요.
but he is already in a tight spot after he let out the APB.
하지만 그는 APB를 나온 이후 이미 곤경에 처해 있다.
Yes, so who on earth is this Inspector Song?
네, 그렇다면 이 송 경감은 도대체 누구입니까?
One of the two people I respect the most.
제가 가장 존경하는 두 분 중 한 분입니다.
On Behavioral Analysis Team? The profilers?
행동분석팀에서요? 프로파일러?
Yes.
예.
After I heard something from Inspector song on my first day,
첫날 경감님의 노래를 듣고 나서
I never once regretted...
단 한 번도 후회한 적이 없어요...
volunteering to join the Behavioral Analysis Team.
행동분석팀에 자원해서 합류하게 되었습니다.
What did he say?
그가 뭐라고 말했습니까?
He asked me that day for the reason why I volunteered.
그날 그는 나에게 자원봉사를 하는 이유를 물었다.
Nothing really came to my mind,
정말 아무것도 떠오르지 않았는데,
so I immaturely replied, "Because it seemed cool."
그래서 "멋져보여서"라고 철없게 대답했다.
He said this to me after a while.
그는 잠시 후에 나에게 이렇게 말했다.
Do you know the story of the blind man and a lantern?
맹인과 등불 이야기를 아시나요?
Someone asked a blind man...
어떤 사람이 시각 장애인에게 물었습니다.
who was walking down a dark road with a lantern in his hand.
등불을 손에 들고 어두운 길을 걷고 있던 사람.
You can't see anyway. Why do you carry that around?
어쨌든 볼 수는 없습니다. 그걸 왜 들고 다니나요?
Why do you think so?
왜 그렇게 생각하시나요?
He wanted others to see clearly and not fall down while walking.
그는 다른 사람들이 걸을 때 넘어지지 않고 명확하게 볼 수 있기를 원했습니다.
I see. That's cool. A lantern.
알겠어요. 멋지네요. 랜턴.
(Victim's profile: Han Seok Hoon, Yang Kyung Hee)
(피해자 프로필 : 한석훈, 양경희)
(Kwon Hyun Sook, 54, Female Many impacts on the head)
(권현숙, 54, 여성 머리에 충격이 많이 가해짐)
Then tell me his name too.
그럼 그 사람 이름도 알려주세요.
- Inspector Song Ha Young. - Song Ha Young?
- 송하영 경위. - 송하영?
- Honey. - Hey, honey.
- 꿀. - 안녕, 자기야.
- Did I keep you waiting? - I just got off.
- 내가 계속 기다리게 했나요? - 방금 내렸어요.
- It's raining a lot. - Yes.
- 비가 많이 오네요. - 예.
- Can you put it in here? - Okay, sure.
- 여기에 넣어도 되나요? - 알았어, 물론이지.
- Yes, okay. Thank you. - Sure.
- 응, 알았어. 감사합니다. - 확신하는.
- Enjoy. - Goodbye.
- 즐기다. - 안녕히 가세요.
My gosh, why is it raining so much?
맙소사, 비가 왜 이렇게 많이 오나요?
I'm home.
나는 집에있다.
Mom?
엄마?
The receiver cannot be reached.
수신자에게 연락할 수 없습니다.
I'm sorry. I'm late.
죄송합니다. 나는 늦었다.
Why didn't you pick up your phone?
왜 전화를 받지 않았나요?
I left it at the bakery.
빵집에 두고 왔습니다.
When I went back, they were already closed.
다시 가보니 이미 문이 닫혀 있었습니다.
You didn't have to get this.
당신은 이것을 얻을 필요가 없었습니다.
And from now on, tell me to get these.
그리고 이제부터 이거 가져오라고 해주세요.
No.
아니요.
I'm much better than you at picking out food ingredients.
나는 너보다 식재료 고르는 걸 훨씬 잘해.
Goodness, I'm glad I made the soup earlier.
맙소사, 수프를 일찍 만들어서 다행이에요.
Honey, you should also celebrate Ha Young's birthday with us.
여보, 하영이의 생일도 우리와 함께 축하해주세요.
The sky is blue, and cherry blossoms are in full blossom.
하늘은 파랗고, 벚꽃은 활짝 피어있습니다.
The weather continues to stay nice and makes us feel warm.
날씨가 계속해서 선선해져서 기분이 따뜻해집니다.
The temperature will rise tomorrow,
내일은 기온이 올라가겠습니다
and it'll be a bit hotter in the south like early summer.
그리고 남부지방은 초여름처럼 조금 더 더워지겠습니다.
But the air is a bit drier.
하지만 공기는 좀 더 건조해요.
In Chungcheong and Gangwon Provinces...
충청도, 강원도에도…
- What's that? - Daily case report.
- 그게 뭐죠? - 일일 사례보고.
I said we won't return to the office...
우리 사무실로 돌아오지 않겠다고 말했는데...
after visiting the prison,
감옥을 방문한 후,
and Woo Ju gave these to me.
그리고 우주주가 이걸 나한테 줬어.
Where did we find such treasure like that kid?
그 아이 같은 보물은 어디서 찾았나요?
I think I still have the luck to be with good people.
아직은 좋은 사람들과 함께할 수 있는 행운이 남아있는 것 같아요.
Am I included in that luck?
나도 그 행운에 포함되는 걸까?
Why? Do you think you aren't?
왜? 당신은 그렇지 않다고 생각하시나요?
You're worried over nothing.
당신은 아무 것도 걱정하지 않습니다.
- Nothing, right? - No.
- 아무것도 아니죠? - 아니.
No, but I'm not sure if that's good or finding something is good.
아니요, 하지만 그게 좋은 것인지, 뭔가를 찾는 것이 좋은 것인지는 잘 모르겠습니다.
I wouldn't feel so frustrated only if we could figure out...
우리가 알아낼 수만 있다면 그렇게 좌절감을 느끼지 않을 것입니다 ...
if he stopped or changed his MO.
그가 MO를 중단하거나 변경한 경우.
A residential district, in public, stabbed in the right side,
주거지역, 공공장소 오른쪽에 찔려
serious injury inflicted by the stab.
칼에 찔려 심각한 부상을 입었습니다.
Camping knife?
캠핑칼?
- Camping knife? - Yes.
- 캠핑용 칼? - 예.
Why?
왜?
May I see that again?
다시 볼 수 있을까요?
- Which one? Sinheung 4-dong? - Yes.
- 어느 것? 신흥4동? - 예.
This is just an assault case.
이건 그냥 폭행 사건이에요.
- May I see it? - Which one? Right here?
- 좀 봐도 될까요? - 어느 것? 바로 여기요?
"April 15, 3:30am."
"4월 15일 오전 3시 30분."
"A residential district, in public, victim, female."
"주거지, 공공장소, 피해자, 여성."
"Serious injury inflicted by the stab on the right side."
"오른쪽 옆구리에 찔려 심각한 부상을 입었습니다."
- "Weapon, camping knife." - Camping knife.
- "무기, 캠핑용 칼." - 캠핑용 칼.
Camping knife.
캠핑칼.
(Attacked with a camping knife.)
(캠핑칼로 공격한다.)
Could you please make a call to Woo Ju?
우주에게 전화 좀 걸어 주시겠어요?
Sure. One second.
확신하는. 1초.
Hey, Woo Ju.
안녕, 우주.
Can you look up "camping knife" and find some reports?
"캠핑 나이프"를 검색해 보고서를 찾아볼 수 있나요?
- Camping knife? - Yes, this year.
- 캠핑용 칼? - 네, 올해요.
I remember seeing it.
본 기억이 나네요.
One second.
1초.
You should begin with Dongjak Police Station.
동작경찰서부터 시작해야 합니다.
(Dongjak Police Station 1st quarter, 2004, Daily Case Report)
(동작경찰서 1분기, 2004, 일일사건보고)
(Camping knife)
(캠핑칼)
Two cases popped up.
2가지 경우가 나왔습니다.
Two cases?
두 가지 경우?
Yes. In Sinheung 2-dong and Sinheung 5-dong.
예. 신흥2동과 신흥5동에 있습니다.
And both cases took place in February this year.
그리고 두 사건 모두 올해 2월에 일어났습니다.
Tell me about the victims.
피해자들에 대해 말해주세요.
Both of them were women in their 20s.
두 사람 모두 20대 여성이었다.
And they have serious injuries.
그리고 그들은 심각한 부상을 입었습니다.
Both were categorized as assault cases.
둘 다 폭행 사건으로 분류됐다.
Print the case reports.
사례 보고서를 인쇄합니다.
Let's go.
갑시다.
(Conference Room)
(회의실)
Captain Yoon.
윤 선장.
Did you look into it?
조사해 보셨나요?
The cases in Guo-dong and Borim-dong took place...
궈동·보림동 사건 발생…
in January and February.
1월과 2월에.
Captain Yoon. Do you think the culprit is the same guy?
윤 선장. 범인이 같은 사람인 것 같나요?
Both victims had serious injuries.
두 피해자 모두 심각한 부상을 입었습니다.
And they were reported as assault cases.
그리고 이들은 폭행 사건으로 신고됐다.
So both victims can't remember his face, right?
그럼 피해자 두 사람 모두 얼굴을 기억하지 못하는 거겠죠?
They only remember seeing his back when he was running away.
그들은 그가 도망갈 때 그의 뒷모습을 본 것만 기억합니다.
Both victims said that he was short and had a small build.
두 피해자 모두 키가 작고 체구가 작았다고 말했습니다.
But it might be a bit of a leap to say that they were attacked...
하지만 공격을 받았다고 하기에는 좀 과한 표현일지도...
by the same guy.
같은 사람에 의해.
But the wealthy senior citizens who were murdered...
그런데 살해당한 부유한 노인들...
lived in different districts.
서로 다른 지역에 살았습니다.
But even if we assume that his MO changed,
하지만 그의 MO가 바뀌었다고 가정하더라도,
it's still confusing because the victims didn't die.
피해자들이 죽지 않았기 때문에 여전히 혼란스럽습니다.
Both victims were...
두 피해자 모두...
stabbed in the abdomen by a camping knife.
캠핑용 칼로 복부를 찔렀다.
The same weapon and location of the stab wounds.
무기와 자상 위치가 동일합니다.
Based on these factors,
이러한 요인을 바탕으로,
we can deduce that the culprit might be the same guy.
범인이 같은 사람일지도 모른다고 추론할 수 있습니다.
But I'm not sure if that's enough to report this...
하지만 이 정도로 신고할 만큼 충분한지는 잘 모르겠습니다...
as criminal intelligence.
범죄 정보로서.
This part bothers me the most.
이 부분이 가장 마음에 걸립니다.
A 170cm-tall suspect with a small build.
키 170cm에 작은 체격의 용의자.
The description is similar to the guy we're looking for.
설명은 우리가 찾고 있는 사람과 비슷합니다.
This is from Geumcheon Police Station?
금천경찰서에서요?
Yes. I went to school with the detective in charge.
예. 나는 담당 형사와 함께 학교에 갔다.
And we recently had drinks.
그리고 우리는 최근에 술을 마셨습니다.
When he was telling me about the case, something was off.
그가 나에게 사건에 대해 이야기했을 때 뭔가 이상했습니다.
So we looked into this ourselves.
그래서 우리가 직접 조사해봤습니다.
What about this?
이건 어때?
At our last meeting, Inspector Song...
지난 회의에서 송 경위는...
mentioned the possibility that he might change his MO.
MO를 변경할 가능성도 언급했습니다.
I remembered what he said that day.
그날 그가 했던 말이 생각났다.
So we kept an eye out to see if there were any cases,
그래서 우리는 어떤 사례가 있는지 살펴보았습니다.
following a specific pattern.
특정 패턴을 따릅니다.
So these cases...
그래서 이 사건들은...
could have been executed by him? Did I get that right?
그 사람에 의해 처형될 수도 있었나요? 내가 이해한 게 맞나요?
Whether it's true or not,
그것이 사실이든 아니든,
it still bothers me.
그것은 아직도 나를 괴롭힌다.
But this isn't a homicide.
하지만 이건 살인이 아니다.
We don't have any excuse to take over the cases.
우리는 사건을 맡을 변명의 여지가 없습니다.
They are just two assault cases.
그들은 단지 두 건의 폭행 사건입니다.
Let us investigate this ourselves.
이에 대해서는 직접 조사해보자.
Goodness. It's all because of this jerk.
선량. 이게 다 이 놈 때문이에요.
I'm starting to see everything as serial murder.
나는 모든 것을 연쇄 살인으로 보기 시작했습니다.
Whenever we get a case, I immediately think it might be him.
사건이 접수될 때마다 저는 즉시 그 사람일지도 모른다고 생각합니다.
Same here.
여기도 마찬가지입니다.
But these cases don't seem to suit his style.
하지만 이런 경우는 그의 스타일에는 맞지 않는 것 같다.
Whether it's the same guy or not, once there's a reasonable doubt,
같은 사람인지 아닌지, 일단 합리적 의심이 든다면
we must investigate.
우리는 조사해야 합니다.
Even if it might be a waste of time,
시간낭비일지도 모르지만,
that's better than losing him because we didn't try.
우리가 시도하지 않았기 때문에 그를 잃는 것보다 낫습니다.
Woo Ju, you got the reports, right?
우주야, 보고서 받았지?
Are they important cases?
중요한 사건인가요?
- We're not sure yet. - Is it him?
- 아직 확실하지 않아요. - 그 사람인가요?
There's a small possibility if he changed his MO.
MO를 바꾸면 가능성은 거의 없습니다.
We'll be back. Let's go.
우리는 돌아올 것이다. 갑시다.
We'll be back.
우리는 돌아올 것이다.
(For people's safety and happiness)
(국민의 안전과 행복을 위하여)
Okay.
알았어.
(We can find your lost items!)
(분실물을 찾아드립니다!)
The victim is in the hospital now.
피해자는 현재 병원에 입원 중이다.
She needs to rest. So you can't interview her.
그녀는 휴식이 필요합니다. 그러니 그녀를 인터뷰할 수는 없습니다.
- This is her statement. - Okay.
- 이것이 그녀의 진술이다. - 좋아요.
He kept following him, so she even threw her purse at him.
그가 계속 그를 따라다녔기 때문에 그녀는 그에게 지갑을 던지기까지 했습니다.
But he wasn't interested in that.
그러나 그는 그런 것에는 관심이 없었습니다.
How did you confirm it was a camping knife?
캠핑용 칼인지 어떻게 확인하셨나요?
Given the size of the stab wound,
찔린 상처의 크기를 고려하면,
we knew it wasn't a kitchen knife.
우리는 그것이 부엌칼이 아니라는 것을 알고 있었습니다.
The victim also said that the knife was small.
피해자는 칼도 작았다고 말했다.
It came up to about a half of our palms.
우리 손바닥 반 정도까지 올라왔어요.
I showed her a few photos.
나는 그녀에게 사진 몇 장을 보여주었다.
She said camping knives looked the closest.
그녀는 캠핑용 칼이 가장 가까운 것 같다고 말했습니다.
- Was there an eyewitness? - Yes.
- 목격자가 있었나요? - 예.
He heard screams, so he opened the window and yelled.
그는 비명소리를 듣고 창문을 열고 소리쳤다.
Then the culprit ran away.
그러자 범인은 도망갔습니다.
He was short, skinny, and balding.
그는 키가 작고, 말랐으며, 대머리였습니다.
He was wearing a shabby tracksuit.
그는 허름한 운동복을 입고 있었습니다.
Can we meet with him?
그 사람을 만날 수 있을까요?
Sure.
확신하는.
And what about the other two cases?
그리고 나머지 두 가지 경우는 어떻습니까?
The other two cases?
나머지 두 사건은요?
Two cases with a similar MO took place in February.
지난 2월에는 유사한 MO를 가진 두 건의 사례가 발생했습니다.
Take a look here.
여기를 보세요.
- Sinheung 5-dong. - Okay.
- 신흥5동. - 좋아요.
Sinheung 2-dong.
신흥2동.
You need to ask the team in charge. I don't have information on them.
담당팀에 문의하셔야 합니다. 나는 그들에 대한 정보가 없습니다.
He's in charge. Detective Kim, come here.
그는 책임자입니다. 김 형사님, 이리 오세요.
He followed her to the door of her house.
그는 그녀를 따라 그녀의 집 문으로 갔다.
He stabbed her when she had her key in the hole.
그녀가 구멍에 열쇠를 넣었을 때 그는 그녀를 찔렀습니다.
He sounded like a total nutcase.
그는 완전히 미친 사람처럼 들렸다.
Did he try to steal her wallet?
그 사람이 지갑을 훔치려고 한 걸까요?
After stabbing her, he left without even touching her bag.
그는 그녀를 찌른 뒤 가방에도 손을 대지 않은 채 떠났다.
So the victim was about to go in.
그래서 피해자가 들어가려고 했어요.
And this jerk came at her all of a sudden.
그리고 이 멍청이가 갑자기 그녀에게 다가왔습니다.
He grabbed her arm and turned her around.
그는 그녀의 팔을 잡고 그녀를 돌렸다.
Then he stabbed her right away.
그런 다음 그는 즉시 그녀를 찔렀습니다.
She couldn't remember his face as she was shocked.
그녀는 충격을 받아 그의 얼굴을 기억하지 못했다.
She said he was short. Right.
그녀는 그가 키가 작다고 말했습니다. 오른쪽.
He was about 170cm tall.
키는 170cm쯤 됐어요.
Not having surveillance cameras in a blind spot like this...
이렇게 사각지대에 감시카메라가 없으면...
is always a problem.
항상 문제입니다.
But we have more cameras compared to last year.
하지만 작년에 비해 카메라가 더 많아졌습니다.
This is an improvement.
이는 개선된 사항입니다.
Right. That's good.
오른쪽. 좋아요.
- But we still need more. - Right.
- 하지만 아직은 더 필요해요. - 오른쪽.
- Is that the house? - Yes. The one on the second floor.
- 저게 집이에요? - 예. 2층에 있는 곳이에요.
That's where I screamed.
내가 비명을 질렀던 곳이 바로 그 곳이었다.
Where was the culprit?
범인은 어디에 있었나요?
Over there. Under the street lamp.
저기요. 가로등 아래.
Something seemed off, so I was watching them.
뭔가 이상한 것 같아서 지켜보고 있었어요.
All of a sudden, the woman started screaming.
갑자기 여자가 비명을 지르기 시작했다.
So I screamed, "Hey! What are you doing?"
그래서 나는 “야! 뭐하는 거야?”라고 소리쳤습니다.
When I screamed,
내가 비명을 질렀을 때,
he ran away. And he was really fast.
그는 도망쳤다. 그리고 그는 정말 빨랐습니다.
You also said that he was short.
키가 작다고도 하셨어요.
He was short.
그는 키가 작았습니다.
He was losing hair. He had a bald spot on his head.
그는 머리카락을 잃고있었습니다. 그는 머리에 대머리 반점이 있었습니다.
Didn't he wear hiking boots?
그 사람 등산화를 신지 않았나요?
I'm not sure about that.
나는 그것에 대해 잘 모르겠습니다.
Right. You were pretty far.
오른쪽. 꽤 멀리 계셨습니다.
What do you mean by he was fast?
그 사람이 빨랐다는 게 무슨 말이야?
The light was bright, so I could see him running away.
빛이 밝아서 그가 도망가는 모습이 보였습니다.
Enough for you to see that he was a fast runner?
그가 빠른 주자라는 것을 알 수 있을 만큼 충분합니까?
Yes. I was surprised how fast he was.
예. 나는 그가 얼마나 빠른지 놀랐다.
The victim suspected it could've been an act of retaliation.
피해자는 보복행위일 수도 있다고 의심했다.
So we also thought that he knew the victim personally.
그래서 우리는 그가 피해자를 개인적으로 알고 있다고 생각했습니다.
And we started questioning her friends.
그리고 우리는 그녀의 친구들에게 질문하기 시작했습니다.
So you didn't find any fingerprints or evidence for both cases?
그렇다면 두 사건 모두 지문이나 증거를 찾지 못했다는 겁니까?
Right. He followed her...
오른쪽. 그는 그녀를 따라갔다...
to her house as if he was determined to hurt her.
마치 그녀를 해치려는 듯이 그녀의 집으로 찾아왔습니다.
She wasn't sure if he was following her.
그녀는 그가 그녀를 따르고 있는지 확신하지 못했습니다.
But he came into the building too.
그런데 그 사람도 건물 안으로 들어왔어요.
And she looked when he took out something from his jacket.
그리고 그녀는 그가 재킷에서 무언가를 꺼내는 것을 보았습니다.
And he stabbed her right away.
그리고 그는 즉시 그녀를 찔렀습니다.
This case took place in Guo-dong.
이번 사건은 궈동에서 일어났습니다.
But it's the same MO with Borim-dong.
그런데 보림동도 마찬가지다.
Only the location changed. And no evidence either.
위치만 바뀌었습니다. 그리고 증거도 없습니다.
On top of that, it rained that night.
게다가 그날 밤에는 비가 내렸습니다.
A camping knife, a stab wound in the abdomen,
캠핑용 칼, 복부에 찔린 상처,
and no valuables or money were taken.
귀중품이나 돈은 가져 가지 않았습니다.
She didn't know she was being followed because of the rain.
그녀는 비 때문에 자신이 미행을 당하고 있다는 사실을 몰랐습니다.
The victim was attacked and on the ground.
피해자는 공격을 받고 땅에 쓰러졌습니다.
When he saw a car coming into the alley,
골목으로 들어오는 차를 본 그는
he was surprised and ran away.
그는 놀라서 도망쳤다.
The victims gave similar descriptions. But no luck yet?
피해자들도 비슷한 설명을 했다. 하지만 아직 운이 없나요?
He was short.
그는 키가 작았습니다.
And when she was on the ground, she saw his feet running away.
그리고 그녀가 땅 위에 있을 때, 그녀는 그의 발이 도망가는 것을 보았습니다.
He was wearing sneakers.
그는 운동화를 신고 있었습니다.
Not hiking boots?
등산화 아님?
She only said he wore sneakers.
운동화만 신었다고 하더군요.
Sneakers.
운동화.
(Keep people safe, and enforce the law fairly.)
(사람들을 안전하게 보호하고 법을 공정하게 집행하십시오.)
The fact that he didn't take money or valuables bothers me the most.
그 사람이 돈이나 귀중품을 가져가지 않았다는 사실이 가장 마음에 걸립니다.
Right?
오른쪽?
He committed crimes in January and February.
그는 1월과 2월에 범죄를 저질렀다.
It's April, but he hadn't committed any crimes afterward.
4월인데 그 이후에는 아무런 범죄도 저지르지 않았습니다.
Is this the cooling-off period the Analysis Team mentioned?
이게 분석팀이 언급한 냉각기간인가요?
Let's check the scene first.
먼저 현장을 확인해보겠습니다.
Is this the place?
이 곳인가요?
Yes.
예.
- This is way too bright. - Yes.
- 너무 밝네요. - 예.
That's odd.
이상하네요.
Three people had serious stab wounds from a camping knife...
캠핑칼에 3명 심각한 찔려…
after these attacks.
이 공격 후에.
All of them took place late at night.
모두 늦은 밤에 일어났습니다.
All of the victims were young women.
피해자는 모두 젊은 여성이었다.
The only difference is...
유일한 차이점은...
one of them happened in an alley at a residential area.
그 중 하나는 주택가의 골목에서 일어났습니다.
And the other two, in front of the victims' houses.
그리고 나머지 두 명은 피해자 집 앞에 있었습니다.
They were attacked in different locations,
서로 다른 곳에서 공격을 받았는데,
but having three cases with the same MO...
그런데 MO가 같은 케이스가 3개 있는데...
implies that there might be more cases.
더 많은 경우가 발생할 수 있음을 의미합니다.
And all of the victims were stabbed...
그리고 피해자들은 모두 칼에 찔렸는데...
in their stomachs.
그들의 뱃속에.
Do you think it's him?
그 사람인 것 같아?
I doubt it.
나는 그것을 의심한다.
The weapon, MO, and time don't match at all.
무기, MO, 시간이 전혀 일치하지 않습니다.
But they seem to have a similar build.
하지만 비슷한 구조를 가지고 있는 것 같습니다.
Right. That's why we can't be certain.
오른쪽. 그렇기 때문에 우리는 확신할 수 없습니다.
But he said the culprit was a fast runner.
그런데 범인은 빠른 주자였다고 하더군요.
If he was visibly fast,
만약 그가 눈에 띄게 빨랐다면,
I don't think he could've done that in hiking boots.
내 생각엔 그가 등산화를 신고 그런 짓을 할 수는 없었을 것 같아요.
Right. You can't run fast in hiking boots.
오른쪽. 등산화를 신은 채 빨리 달릴 수는 없습니다.
There's a photo of him from behind, and we know he wore hiking boots.
그의 뒤에서 찍은 사진이 있는데, 우리는 그가 등산화를 신었다는 것을 알고 있습니다.
So he probably didn't wear them.
그래서 그는 아마도 그것을 입지 않았을 것입니다.
But the culprit we're looking for...
하지만 우리가 찾고 있는 범인은...
brutally murdered his victims with a blunt weapon,
둔기 등으로 피해자를 잔인하게 살해하고,
not even giving the victims to resist.
피해자들에게 저항할 기회도 주지 않습니다.
Even if he wanted to change the MO, I don't think he would use...
MO를 바꾸고 싶어도 사용하지 않을 것 같은데...
such a small knife.
이렇게 작은 칼.
Let's say that it is him.
그 사람이라고 가정 해 봅시다.
All of these assault cases would be attempted murder cases.
이런 폭행 사건은 모두 살인미수 사건이 된다.
That wouldn't have satisfied him.
그것은 그를 만족시키지 못했을 것입니다.
Then he wouldn't have used the same weapon three times.
그렇다면 그는 같은 무기를 세 번 사용하지 않았을 것입니다.
Seeing how he repeated his crimes, can't we interpret that...
그가 반복적으로 범행을 저지르는 것을 보면, 그렇게 해석할 수는 없을까...
he didn't know if the victims were dead or not?
그 사람은 피해자가 죽었는지 안 죽었는지 몰랐나요?
Even if you're right, that doesn't change anything.
당신이 옳다고 해도 달라지는 건 없습니다.
He rarely left any evidence after breaking into the houses.
그는 집에 침입한 후 증거를 거의 남기지 않았습니다.
Someone like him followed his victims?
그와 같은 사람이 피해자를 추적했다고요?
There could've been witnesses. He wouldn't take risks like that...
목격자가 있었을 수도 있어요. 그는 그런 위험을 감수하지 않을 것입니다 ...
because he's super careful.
왜냐면 그 사람은 정말 조심스럽거든요.
What if it's not him?
그 사람이 아니면 어쩌지?
Since all the victims were injured,
피해자들이 모두 부상을 입었기 때문에
we're not looking for a murderer, but a violent man who robs people.
우리가 찾는 것은 살인자가 아니라, 사람의 물건을 빼앗는 폭력적인 사람입니다.
No. He wasn't interested in valuables. He's not a robber.
아니요. 그는 귀중품에는 관심이 없었습니다. 그는 강도가 아닙니다.
What if our guess is right?
우리의 추측이 맞다면 어떨까요?
What if the victims were only injured...
피해자만 부상당했다면..
because he couldn't finish the job?
그 사람이 일을 끝내지 못했기 때문에?
Then...
그럼...
we have two serial murderers in this country.
이 나라에는 두 명의 연쇄 살인범이 있습니다.
(Mr. Kwak in Mapo, Girls in their 20s)
(마포 곽씨, 20대 여학생)
This one didn't die either?
이 사람도 죽지 않았나요?
The same weapon was used in the three cases.
세 경우 모두 동일한 무기가 사용되었습니다.
A camping knife?
캠핑용 칼?
Look, these three locations...
보세요, 이 세 곳은...
aren't far from each other.
서로 멀지 않습니다.
The type of weapon, where the victims were attacked,
피해자가 공격받은 무기의 종류,
and even the time. These cases have a lot in common.
그리고 심지어 시간. 이 사건들은 공통점이 많습니다.
"Seriously injured..."
"심각한 부상…"
Why? We can't investigate them because they're not murders?
왜요? 살인이 아니니까 수사할 수는 없잖아요?
Is there something else?
다른 것이 있나요?
Where are you going?
어디 가세요?
Captain Yoon, come here for a moment.
윤 대위님, 잠시 이리로 오세요.
Guo-dong, Borim-dong.
궈동, 보림동.
These cases took place in January and February of this year.
이번 사건은 올해 1월과 2월에 발생했다.
We believe these were done by the culprit...
우리는 이것이 범인에 의해 행해진 것이라고 믿습니다...
of the serial murders. We're investigating at the moment.
연쇄 살인의. 현재 조사 중입니다.
It's not the same guy.
같은 사람이 아닙니다.
What?
무엇?
This is a different guy.
이 사람은 다른 사람입니다.
But the height and the build look similar.
하지만 키와 체격은 비슷해 보인다.
But they have nothing else in common.
하지만 그 외에는 공통점이 없습니다.
From the MO to the weapons, everything's different.
MO부터 무기까지 모든 것이 다릅니다.
Didn't you say the MO could change?
MO가 바뀔 수 있다고 하지 않았나요?
Yes, it could change.
예, 바뀔 수 있습니다.
But he already got a taste of killing people with a blunt weapon.
하지만 그는 이미 둔기로 사람을 죽이는 맛을 느꼈습니다.
There's no way he's now using a camping knife, which is smaller.
이제 그가 더 작은 캠핑용 칼을 사용할 리가 없습니다.
Then there's an even lesser chance that this is a serial case, right?
그렇다면 연쇄 사건일 가능성은 더욱 낮겠죠?
These victims didn't die.
이 피해자들은 죽지 않았습니다.
Thankfully, the victims didn't die.
다행히 피해자들은 죽지 않았다.
But it could actually make the culprit even more violent.
하지만 실제로는 범인을 더욱 폭력적으로 만들 수도 있습니다.
We must catch him...
우리는 그를 잡아야 해...
before there's another victim.
또 다른 피해자가 생기기 전에
What are you talking about?
무슨 얘기를 하는 건가요?
This serial killer is already giving us a huge headache.
이 연쇄 살인범은 이미 우리에게 큰 골칫거리를 안겨주고 있습니다.
How will we track down a murder that hasn't even happened yet?
아직 일어나지도 않은 살인 사건을 어떻게 추적할 것인가?
Let's draw a facial composite.
얼굴 합성을 그려 봅시다.
Yes, let's start with a facial composite.
예, 얼굴 합성부터 시작해 보겠습니다.
All the victims are alive.
피해자들은 모두 살아있습니다.
And we have a witness too, so it can be done.
그리고 증인도 있으니 그렇게 할 수 있습니다.
The victims are still traumatized...
피해자들은 아직도 트라우마가 남아있습니다..
and don't remember his face.
그리고 그 사람 얼굴도 기억나지 않아요.
Let's try forensic hypnosis.
법의학 최면을 시도해 봅시다.
He has a slim face.
그는 날씬한 얼굴을 가지고 있습니다.
(Use of hypnosis in the investigative process to find clues)
(단서를 찾기 위한 수사 과정에서 최면을 활용함)
He has small, slanted eyes.
그는 작고 비스듬한 눈을 가지고 있습니다.
And...
그리고...
Oh...
아...
He looks like he's losing hair.
그는 머리카락이 빠지고 있는 것처럼 보입니다.
Where? At the hairline on the forehead?
어디? 이마 헤어라인에?
Yes.
예.
(National Forensic Service)
(국립과학수사연구원)
As you know, the killer isn't after money.
아시다시피 범인은 돈을 노리는 게 아닙니다.
(Facial Composite)
(얼굴 합성)
If it's not about money or personal grudges,
돈이나 개인적인 원한이 아니라면
there can be only one goal.
목표는 하나만 있을 수 있습니다.
Killing.
죽이는.
(Facial Composite)
(얼굴 합성)
Yes, he looked like this.
네, 그는 이렇게 생겼습니다.
He was skinny. He had a skinny face like this.
그는 마른 체형이었습니다. 그 사람은 이렇게 마른 얼굴을 갖고 있었거든요.
This is pretty accurate.
이것은 꽤 정확합니다.
- Thank you. - No problem.
- 감사합니다. - 괜찮아요.
- Thank you. - No problem at all.
- 감사합니다. - 전혀 문제 없습니다.
Let's go.
갑시다.
Oh, you're here.
아, 여기 계시군요.
Take a look at this.
이것 좀 보세요.
We had the witness verify the accuracy of this composite.
우리는 목격자에게 이 합성물의 정확성을 확인하도록 했습니다.
Looks good, right?
괜찮아 보이는데요?
So this scum may be the one who killed the senior citizens.
그러니까 이 쓰레기가 노인들을 죽인 게 아닐까.
It's not the same guy.
같은 사람이 아닙니다.
No.
아니요.
We'll continue to investigate keeping in mind the possibility...
가능성을 염두에 두고 계속 조사해보겠습니다.
that it could be the same guy.
같은 사람일 수도 있다는 것.
Whether it's the same guy or not,
같은 사람인지 아닌지,
we're investigating the same case, aren't we?
우리도 같은 사건을 조사하고 있지 않나요?
- Yes, we are. - Very well.
- 네, 그렇습니다. - 아주 좋아요.
- Let's go through it again. - Okay.
- 다시 한번 살펴보겠습니다. - 좋아요.
It took place late at night...
늦은 밤에 일어난 일인데..
under a brightly lit street lamp.
환하게 켜진 가로등 아래.
The Borim-dong case also took place under a street lamp.
보림동 사건도 가로등 밑에서 벌어졌다.
Normally, perpetrators...
보통 가해자는...
look for dark spots to hide themselves.
자신을 숨길 수 있는 어두운 점을 찾으세요.
And the victims were attacked from the front, not from behind.
그리고 피해자들은 뒤에서가 아닌 앞에서 공격을 받았다.
Did he reveal his face on purpose?
일부러 얼굴을 공개한 걸까요?
- Hold on. Watch this. - Okay.
- 기다리다. 이것을 보세요. - 좋아요.
The victim...
피해자는 ...
was walking this way.
이쪽으로 걷고 있었어요.
She suddenly felt that someone was following her.
그녀는 갑자기 누군가가 자신을 따라오고 있다는 느낌을 받았습니다.
She threw her purse, so he'd just take it and leave.
그녀는 지갑을 던졌고 그는 그냥 가지고 떠나곤 했습니다.
But he didn't care about the purse and kept following her,
하지만 그는 지갑에는 개의치 않고 계속해서 그녀를 따라다녔고,
so she started walking fast, terrified.
그래서 그녀는 겁에 질려 빠르게 걷기 시작했습니다.
The culprit must've continued to follow her.
범인은 계속 그녀를 따라다녔나 보다.
Then he suddenly swung his knife at her.
그러더니 갑자기 그녀에게 칼을 휘둘렀다.
- Hold on. - He made her turn around.
- 기다리다. - 그는 그녀를 돌아서게 만들었어요.
But it could've happened the moment she happened to turn around.
하지만 그녀가 우연히 돌아선 순간에 그런 일이 일어났을 수도 있다.
The one thing these cases have in common is that...
이 사건들의 공통점은..
the victims were stabbed in their abdomen.
피해자들은 복부에 칼을 찔렸습니다.
They were all attacked from the front.
그들은 모두 정면에서 공격을 받았습니다.
They all took place in the southwestern part of the city.
그들은 모두 도시의 남서부 지역에서 일어났습니다.
Could it be someone who lives in the area?
그 지역에 사는 사람이 아닐까?
Why does the Special Crime Squad think that these cases...
특수수사대는 왜 이런 사건들을...
were committed by the culprit who killed the rich senior citizens?
부자 노인들을 죽인 범인이 저질렀다고?
That scum targeted houses in the affluent neighborhoods...
그 쓰레기는 부유한 동네의 집을 표적으로 삼았는데...
of Gangnam and Gangbuk.
강남과 강북.
But as you can see on this map, this isn't a rich neighborhood.
하지만 이 지도에서 볼 수 있듯이 이곳은 부유한 동네가 아닙니다.
Let's go through everything again.
모든 것을 다시 살펴 보겠습니다.
Our theory is that he attacked the victims to kill them.
우리의 이론은 그가 피해자들을 죽이기 위해 공격했다는 것입니다.
And these attacks took place five times in southwestern Seoul.
그리고 이러한 공격은 서울 남서부 지역에서 5차례나 발생했습니다.
That could mean he didn't know that the victims didn't die.
피해자가 죽지 않았다는 사실을 몰랐다는 뜻일 수도 있다.
Do you think his MO will change once he finds out they didn't die?
그들이 죽지 않았다는 사실을 알게 되면 그의 MO가 바뀔 것이라고 생각합니까?
It's highly likely.
가능성이 높습니다.
If he didn't know they didn't die,
몰랐다면 그들은 죽지 않았을 것이다.
and if that was why he kept using the same MO,
그래서 계속 같은 MO를 사용했다면,
these "attacks"...
이 "공격"...
could turn into murders once he finds out.
그가 알게 되면 살인으로 변할 수도 있다.
In fact, that is what I'm most worried about.
사실 그게 가장 걱정이에요.
Then how would he find out?
그러면 그 사람은 어떻게 알 수 있겠습니까?
Through the news or the newspapers, probably.
아마도 뉴스나 신문을 통해서일 겁니다.
Or he could visit the scenes again.
아니면 현장을 다시 방문할 수도 있습니다.
You said it rained when the attack took place.
공격이 일어났을 때 비가 왔다고 하더군요.
Yes.
예.
You can't see clearly when it's raining,
비오면 잘 안보이는데,
which makes things easier for the perpetrator.
가해자의 일이 더 쉬워집니다.
On top of choosing a brightly lit spot,
조명이 밝은 곳을 선택하는 것 외에도
he purposely revealed his face. Why?
일부러 얼굴을 공개했다. 왜?
This wasn't about a personal grudge, so why did he reveal his face?
개인적인 원한이 아닌데 왜 얼굴을 공개한 걸까요?
Why? Why did he do that?
왜? 왜 그랬나요?
I really don't get it.
정말 이해가 안 돼요.
What time did the incident take place?
사건이 발생한 시간은 언제입니까?
Around 9pm.
오후 9시쯤.
Let's go back to the scene in Borim-dong.
다시 보림동 현장으로 돌아가 보겠습니다.
Yes, ma'am.
네, 부인.
So we'll check this area every day from now on, right?
그럼 우리 이제부터 이 부분을 매일 확인하도록 할게요, 그렇죠?
Yes.
예.
Do you really think the culprit will return to the scene?
정말로 범인이 현장에 돌아올 것이라고 생각하시나요?
First, we have to put ourselves in his shoes.
먼저, 우리는 그의 입장에서 생각해야 합니다.
Why did he choose these areas?
그는 왜 이 지역을 선택했는가?
Did he look for easy spots where he can attack someone and run?
누군가를 공격하고 도망갈 수 있는 쉬운 지점을 찾았나요?
Or is he familiar with this area?
아니면 이 분야에 대해 잘 아는 사람인가요?
Gosh, this feels like a waste of time.
맙소사, 이건 시간낭비인 것 같아.
I feel like we're on a stakeout...
우리가 측량을 하고 있는 것 같아...
because of something that hasn't even happened yet.
아직 일어나지도 않은 일 때문에.
No, we're not. We're trying to track down...
아니요, 그렇지 않습니다. 추적 중입니다...
a serial killer who has already committed murders.
이미 살인을 저지른 연쇄 살인범.
It is the same case, but remember that we're looking at it...
같은 경우지만, 우리가 보고 있다는 것을 기억하세요...
from a different perspective,
다른 관점에서,
on the premise that it's the same guy.
같은 사람이라는 전제 하에.
(Pureumae Park, Dongjak-gu)
(동작구 푸른매공원)
This morning at Seoul Pureumae Park...
오늘 아침 서울 푸른매공원에서..
a woman in her 20s was found stabbed to death.
20대 여성이 흉기에 찔려 숨진 채 발견됐다.
The victim had been stabbed with a knife multiple times...
피해자는 칼에 수차례 찔렸는데…
and had been bleeding a lot when she was found.
발견 당시 피를 많이 흘리고 있었습니다.
People were heartbroken to hear she passed away in the ambulance...
그녀가 구급차에서 세상을 떠났다는 소식에 사람들은 가슴이 아팠습니다...
on the way to the hospital.
병원으로 가는 길.
The crime occurred at a blind spot...
범행은 사각지대에서 발생…
where no CCTVs were installed.
CCTV가 설치되지 않은 곳.
It's been a struggle to find traces of the culprit due to no witnesses.
목격자가 없어 범인의 흔적을 찾는데 애를 먹었다.
The importance of having safety measures in parks...
공원 내 안전 조치의 중요성
has been raised with this incident.
이번 사건으로 제기됐습니다.
Seoul City has announced that...
서울시가 밝혔는데요..
they will inspect the park's street lamps...
그들은 공원의 가로등을 검사할 것입니다...
and install more CCTVs to remove blind spots.
사각지대를 없애기 위해 CCTV를 더 설치해야 합니다.
(Map of Seoul Metropolitan City)
(서울시 지도)
The Pureumae Case...
푸르매 사건...
also occurred in the southern district of Seoul.
서울 남부 지역에서도 발생했습니다.
This happened at a park though, not a residential street.
주택가가 아닌 공원에서 일어난 일입니다.
On top of that, the weapon wasn't a camping knife but a kitchen knife.
게다가 무기는 캠핑칼이 아닌 부엌칼이었다.
You're seeing this as the same punk when it is this different?
이렇게 다른데 이걸 같은 놈으로 보는 겁니까?
Or is it a third suspect or something?
아니면 세 번째 용의자인가?
Come on, just hear him out.
어서, 그의 말을 들어보세요.
Carry on.
계속하세요.
Woman in her 20s with stab wounds in her stomach.
배에 찔린 상처를 입은 20대 여성.
The time of the crime and area of attack...
범행시간과 공격지역..
match with the other victims.
다른 피해자들과 일치합니다.
Although it's a park...
공원이기는 하지만..
it's a shortcut from the subway to the residential area...
지하철에서 주택가로 가는 지름길인데...
so residents of this neighborhood used this route often.
그래서 이 동네 주민들은 이 길을 자주 이용했어요.
Why does that matter?
그게 왜 중요해요?
I'm saying, it has to be considered as a residential street also.
주거지역으로도 생각해야 한다는 거죠.
We have a description of the suspect too.
용의자에 대한 설명도 있어요.
Wait, there was a witness?
잠깐, 목격자가 있었다고요?
No.
아니요.
The victim gave testimony...
피해자 증언..
while being transported into the ambulance.
구급차로 이송되는 동안.
I guess...
아마도...
she was alive up until then.
그녀는 그때까지 살아 있었습니다.
It was a man in his 30s, about 170cm in height...
키 170cm정도의 30대 남성이었는데..
with little hair...
작은 머리로...
dressed in dark workout clothes.
어두운 운동복을 입고 있다.
In a phone call with her boyfriend right after the incident, she said,
사건 직후 A씨는 남자친구와 통화에서 이렇게 말했다.
"A stranger followed me and stabbed me with a knife."
"낯선 사람이 따라오더니 칼로 찔렀어요."
The conversation ended with that.
대화는 그것으로 끝났다.
Just as we feared...
우리가 두려워했던 것처럼...
the culprit wasn't satisfied with his last crime.
범인은 그의 마지막 범죄에 만족하지 않았습니다.
So our guess is that he committed another crime...
그래서 우리는 그가 또 다른 범죄를 저질렀다고 추측합니다...
with a larger and sharper weapon.
더 크고 더 날카로운 무기로.
- I still disagree. - With what?
- 아직도 동의하지 않습니다. - 무엇으로요?
I disagree with everything that the Analysis Team says.
나는 분석팀이 말하는 모든 것에 동의하지 않습니다.
Don't you think it's time we stop being swayed by them?
이제 우리가 그들에게 더 이상 휘둘리지 않을 때가 되지 않았나요?
- Darn it. - Gosh, that temper of his.
- 젠장. - 맙소사, 그 사람 성격이 그래요.
Just let him be.
그냥 그대로 두세요.
So then the Analysis Team thinks...
그러면 분석팀에서는 이렇게 생각합니다.
that the culprit of the Southwest Case and this one...
사우스웨스트 사건의 범인과 이건...
is the same guy, right?
같은 사람 맞죠?
Yes. If you take a look at the pictures from the scene...
예. 현장 사진을 보시면..
it's neither sexual assault nor mugging.
성폭행도 아니고 강도도 아니다.
It's a different guy from the serial murders of the rich elderly then?
그렇다면 부자노인연쇄살인과는 다른 놈인가?
Yes.
예.
I don't want to say this...
나는 이런 말을 하고 싶지 않다...
but we have to catch...
하지만 우리는 잡아야 해...
two serial murderers.
두 명의 연쇄 살인범.
Don't blow this matter up hastily.
이 문제를 성급하게 폭로하지 마십시오.
If we announce there are two serial murderers...
연쇄살인범이 2명 있다고 발표하면...
without clear evidence...
명확한 증거도 없이...
the level of anxiety the people will feel will only multiply.
사람들이 느끼는 불안의 수준은 더욱 커질 것입니다.
Their trust in the police will also waver.
경찰에 대한 신뢰도 흔들릴 것이다.
Physical evidence found at the scene is not the only clue.
현장에서 발견된 물적 증거만이 유일한 단서는 아니다.
There are bound to be traces in the time and place he resided that day.
그날 그가 살았던 시간과 장소에는 흔적이 남아있을 것이다.
A trace that may seem trivial...
사소해 보일 수도 있는 흔적...
becomes an important clue to help find the culprit.
범인을 찾는데 중요한 단서가 됩니다.
We can't only look at the weapon, but we must expand the conditions...
무기만 볼 수 있는 게 아니라 조건을 확장해야 하는데...
and look to see if there are any similar cases.
그리고 비슷한 사례가 있는지 살펴보세요.
What are you saying then?
그럼 무슨 말씀이세요?
You want us to request cooperation...
우리에게 협력을 요청하고 싶다고...
from 36 police stations in Seoul?
서울 36개 경찰서에서요?
I think if we can, we must do it.
가능하다면 반드시 해야 한다고 생각합니다.
(Special Crime Squad 1, Team 1)
(특수수사대 1팀)
- Is he serious? - Seriously?
- 그 사람 진심이에요? - 진지하게?
We have so much to do.
우리는 할 일이 너무 많습니다.
- Gosh. - What a headache.
- 이런. - 머리가 아프네요.
Seoul Metropolitan Police Agency and Special Crime Squad...
서울지방경찰청과 특수수사대...
held a meeting with 31 chiefs of police...
경찰서장 31명과 면담…
to solve the serial attacks on women in the southwest of Seoul.
서울 서남부 여성 연쇄테러 사건을 해결하기 위해.
They established an information room for crimes with no motives...
동기도 없이 범죄정보실을 개설했는데..
and announced they'll be increasing cooperative investigations.
협력 조사를 확대하겠다고 발표했습니다.
We are a personal bodyguard service.
우리는 개인 경호원 서비스입니다.
A bodyguard just for myself.
나만을 위한 경호원.
We're starting our special event for these self-defense sprays.
호신용 스프레이를 위한 특별 이벤트를 시작합니다.
Now offering a huge discount.
지금 엄청난 할인 혜택을 제공하고 있습니다.
The reason is...
그 이유는...
With violent crimes targeting women happening consecutively...
여성을 대상으로 한 강력범죄가 연달아 발생하는데…
in the southwestern district of Seoul,
서울 남서부 지역에서,
the level of anxiety has jumped amongst the people.
사람들 사이에서 불안의 수준이 급등했습니다.
Within this year, there have been six cases of attacks in this area.
올해에만 이 지역에서 6건의 공격이 발생했습니다.
It's been revealed that one of these cases was a murder case...
이 사건 중 하나가 살인 사건인 것으로 밝혀졌습니다.
causing huge shock in the community.
커뮤니티에 큰 충격을 주고 있습니다.
We'll connect to Reporter Kim Ju Young.
김주영 기자에게 연결해드리겠습니다.
On the morning of the 16th at Pureumae Park,
16일 오전 푸른매공원.
a murder occurred.
살인이 일어났습니다.
Pureumae Park is looking empty...
푸른매공원은 텅 비어 보이는데...
due to no visitors coming by.
손님이 안 오니까.
One citizen expressed her anxiety by saying...
한 시민은 불안한 마음을 토로했다.
"I'm scared to walk alone, so I'm refraining from going out."
"혼자 걷는 게 무서워서 외출을 자제하고 있어요."
The police have increased the amount of questioning...
경찰, 심문 수위 늘렸다…
and have been doing their best in trying to obtain evidence.
그리고 증거 확보에 최선을 다해왔습니다.
But it seems like they haven't seen much result.
하지만 별로 성과를 보지 못한 것 같습니다.
(Looking for witnesses, 10,000-dollar reward)
(증인찾기, 현상금 1만달러)
("Please report if you saw the victim around 1:30am at this park.")
("새벽 1시 30분쯤 이 공원에서 피해자를 보신 분은 신고해주세요.")
You're coming home way past midnight today too. You must be tired.
오늘도 자정이 넘어서 집에 오시네요. 피곤하겠네요.
- Are you going to the morning mass? - Yes.
- 아침미사에 가시나요? - 예.
I'll drop you off.
내려드릴게요.
Gosh, it's fine. I go there every week anyway.
맙소사, 괜찮아요. 어쨌든 나는 매주 거기에 간다.
It's bright outside already. Don't worry.
밖은 벌써 밝아졌네요. 괜찮아요.
No, I'm going to drop you off. Come on out.
아니, 내가 내려줄게. 나오세요.
My goodness. I told you, it's fine.
이럴 수가. 내가 말했잖아, 괜찮아.
Please think of your servant Michael...
당신의 종 마이클을 생각해 주십시오...
who you called away from this world.
당신이 이 세상에서 불러낸 사람.
He participated in the saint's death through baptism.
그는 세례를 통해 성자의 죽음에 참여했습니다.
So please let him enjoy his resurrection too.
그러니 그 사람도 부활을 즐기게 해주세요.
Those who are sound asleep with the hopes of resurrection...
부활의 소망을 품고 잠들어 있는 자들아...
The devil has hid himself again.
마귀가 또 숨었습니다.
Please think of them...
그들을 생각해 주세요...
and let them meet your shining face.
그리고 그들이 당신의 빛나는 얼굴을 만나게 해주세요.
(July 2004)
(2004년 7월)
Why are they under construction every day?
왜 매일 공사가 진행되는 걸까요?
They're going to build a house at this point.
그들은 이 시점에서 집을 지을 예정이다.
The noise is killing me.
소음이 나를 죽인다.
Police.
경찰.
(Senior Inspector, Kook Young Soo)
(국영수 경감)
I'm a police officer.
저는 경찰관입니다.
Yes, I'm a police officer.
네, 저는 경찰입니다.
"Spooky Thursdays," my gosh.
"으스스한 목요일" 맙소사.
They've stopped night studies at girls' high schools.
그들은 여자 고등학교의 야간 학습을 중단했습니다.
I'm having nightmares every day...
매일 악몽을 꾼다...
because I'm worried this may end up a cold case.
왜냐하면 이 사건이 미해결 사건으로 끝날까 봐 걱정되기 때문입니다.
I think the world is becoming strange.
세상이 이상해지는 것 같아요.
Seriously.
진지하게.
I feel like I'm running in circles.
나는 원을 그리며 달리는 것 같은 느낌이 듭니다.
What does he want to nag about now?
그 사람은 지금 무슨 잔소리를 하고 싶은 걸까?
Yes?
예?
Where are you, Young Soo? Hurry up and come in.
영수야, 어디야? 서둘러서 들어가세요.
Why?
왜?
I think we caught that punk.
내 생각엔 우리가 그 놈을 잡은 것 같아.
"That punk?" Which punk?
"그 새끼?" 어느 펑크?
That punk has a forged ID card.
그 새끼는 위조된 신분증을 가지고 있어요.
Forged ID card? What are you talking about?
위조된 신분증? 무슨 얘기를 하는 건가요?
Don't tell me you're talking about the one I lost four years ago?
내가 4년 전에 잃어버린 사람에 대해 이야기하고 있는 게 아닌가?
Gosh, just stop talking and hurry on over here!
맙소사, 그만 얘기하고 빨리 이리로 와요!
The serial murderer of the wealthy senior citizens...
부유한 노인들을 연쇄 살인범으로...
we caught that punk!
우리가 그 새끼를 잡았어요!
Turn the car around, Ha Young.
차 돌려, 하영아.
(Seoul Metropolitan Police Agency)
(서울지방경찰청)
(Statement Recording Room)
(진술녹음실)
(Personal information)
(개인정보)
You arrested him as a suspect of a sex worker's abduction?
그를 성노동자 납치 용의자로 체포했다고요?
Yes.
예.
The women on the staff continuously couldn't be reached.
여직원들에게 계속해서 연락이 닿지 않았습니다.
The pimp reported him after much suspicion.
포주는 많은 의심 끝에 그를 신고했습니다.
He was arrested around 05:30am today.
그는 오늘 오전 5시 30분쯤 체포됐다.
He had his victim, Gu Young Chun's phone,
피해자인 천구영 씨의 휴대전화를 갖고 있었는데,
as well as articles from the lost women.
잃어버린 여성들의 기사도 있습니다.
Mapo Police Station is done investigating them.
마포경찰서는 이들에 대한 수사를 마쳤다.
We're also in the process of searching through the car...
저희도 차를 수색하는 중인데..
of the woman who went missing two days ago.
이틀 전 실종된 여성의 이야기입니다.
What about the missing victims?
실종된 피해자들은 어떻습니까?
"I killed them. I didn't."
"내가 그들을 죽였어. 난 안 죽였어."
"I buried them. I didn't."
"나는 그것들을 묻었습니다. 나는 묻지 않았습니다."
His statement is everywhere.
그의 발언은 어디에나 있습니다.
Anyway, Chief Kim Bong Sik.
아무튼 김봉식 과장님.
How did you come to catch him together?
어떻게 그 사람을 잡으러 왔나요?
The owner of the business, Kwak Man Hyun,
사업주 곽만현씨
is an acquaintance of Chief Kim Bong Sik.
김봉식 과장의 지인이다.
That's why he's not showing up?
그래서 그 사람이 나타나지 않는 걸까요?
Anyway, are you sure that guy said he did bad stuff...
그나저나 그 사람이 나쁜 짓을 했다고 한 게 확실한가요...
to those elderly people?
그 노인들한테?
Yes, I think so.
네, 그런 것 같아요.
But he kept going off speaking nonsense on our way here.
그런데 그 사람은 여기로 오는 동안에도 계속 말도 안 되는 소리를 하더군요.
What do you think, Inspector Song?
송 경위는 어떻게 생각하시나요?
We should first check...
먼저 확인해 봐야 할 것은...
if he has a mental condition...
그 사람이 정신질환이 있다면..
or a history of receiving personality disorder treatment.
또는 성격 장애 치료를 받은 이력이 있습니다.
Oh, the one you wrote down in the most recent profiling report?
아, 가장 최근 프로파일링 보고서에 적어두셨던 거요?
Yes.
예.
- Detective Nam. - Yes, sir.
- 남 형사님. - 네, 선생님.
- Run over and check. - Yes, sir.
- 달려가서 확인해 보세요. - 네, 선생님.
You!
너!
You're at Seoul Agency's Special Crime Squad.
당신은 서울청 특수수사대에 있습니다.
So get your story straight!
그러니 이야기를 똑바로 하세요!
Did you kill those ladies...
그 아줌마들을 죽였나요...
and buried them in secret too?
그것도 비밀리에 묻었나요?
Yes.
예.
What's this about killing the elderly?
노인을 죽이는 게 무슨 소리야?
What do you think?
어떻게 생각하나요?
I literally killed those old people.
나는 말 그대로 그 노인들을 죽였습니다.
How dare you smile?
어떻게 감히 웃어?
Are you referring to the elderly you killed...
당신이 죽인 노인들을 말하는 겁니까?
as the victims of the murder case of the wealthy senior citizens?
부유한 노인 살인사건의 피해자로?
Detective!
형사!
Gu Young Chun is still under questioning, right?
구영천 씨는 아직도 심문을 받고 있는 거죠?
I came all the way here from Mapo Police Station.
저는 마포경찰서에서 여기까지 왔습니다.
- Can you share something? - I have nothing to share.
- 뭔가 공유할 수 있나요? - 공유할 내용이 없습니다.
Detective!
형사!
Is Jung Woo Ju my only chance?
정우주만이 나에게 기회인가?
Not there. This way. Come.
거기에는 없습니다. 이쪽으로. 오다.
Are you sure this is it?
이것이 확실합니까?
(The date and place of the case October 30, 2003, 32 Hwanghwa-dong)
(사건 발생일자 및 장소 2003년 10월 30일 황화동 32번지)
(Suseong-dong Case)
(수성동 사건)
Write down how many you killed.
몇 명을 죽였는지 적어보세요.
The elderly or the young girls?
노인인가요, 아니면 어린 소녀인가요?
You jerk.
멍청아.
Every single one!
하나하나!
Don't go any further than that.
그 이상 더 이상 가지 마십시오.
What's with him? He keeps ticking me off.
그 사람은 뭐야? 그 사람이 계속 나한테 짜증을 내는 거야.
How dare he smile? Stop smiling, you jerk.
그가 어떻게 감히 미소를 지을 수 있겠는가? 그만 웃어, 이 멍청아.
Man, that jerk.
이봐, 그 멍청이.
Gil Pyo, you should smoke outside.
길표야, 담배는 밖에서 피워라.
Man.
남성.
Keep an eye on him.
그를 계속 지켜보세요.
And let me know right away once Detective Nam calls.
그리고 남 형사가 전화하면 바로 알려주세요.
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
Do you think his words are...
그 사람 말이 맞는 것 같나요?
worth trusting?
믿을만한 가치가 있나요?
I don't think he's lying.
나는 그가 거짓말을 하고 있다고 생각하지 않습니다.
But we'll have to keep an eye on him.
하지만 우리는 그를 계속 지켜봐야 할 것이다.
Why don't you have any instant coffee in the office?
사무실에 인스턴트 커피가 왜 없나요?
It means we can't spare any time to drink coffee.
커피를 마실 시간이 없다는 뜻이다.
You held out here for the last four years?
지난 4년 동안 여기서 버텼나요?
I didn't hold out.
나는 버티지 않았다.
I've been working well with pride.
자부심을 갖고 잘 일해왔습니다.
I went to Mapo Police Station after getting a call...
연락을 받고 마포경찰서로 갔는데..
that they might have a story.
그들에게 이야기가 있을지도 모르니까요.
When I went there, I saw a guy named Gu Young Chun.
거기 갔을 때 구영춘이라는 사람을 봤어요.
He was there as a suspect for murdering sex workers.
그는 성노동자들을 살해한 용의자로 그곳에 있었습니다.
This guy first said he killed and buried many young women,
이 사람은 처음에 젊은 여자들을 많이 죽이고 매장했다고 했는데,
then insisted he didn't.
그런 다음 그는 그렇지 않다고 주장했습니다.
He went on to say he remembers where he buried them, then not.
그는 계속해서 자신이 그것들을 어디에 묻었는지 기억하지만, 그렇지 않다고 말했습니다.
He kept talking nonsense.
그는 계속 말도 안되는 소리를 했습니다.
Then he also said he killed the elderly too.
그러다가 노인들도 죽였다고 하더군요.
Isn't that weird?
그거 이상하지 않아?
Then three detectives of the Seoul Agency...
그렇다면 서울청 형사 3명은…
dragged that man together and left.
그 남자를 끌고 가버렸어요.
That's why I had no choice but to come down here.
그래서 여기까지 내려올 수밖에 없었습니다.
I gave a thought...
생각을 해봤는데...
on Gu Young Chun.
구영천에 대해서.
Do you think...
당신은 생각합니까 ...
he's the one?
그 사람이야?
Don't you want to know where I buried them?
내가 그것들을 어디에 묻었는지 알고 싶지 않나요?
Isn't that why you brought me here?
그래서 날 여기로 데려온 거 아냐?
- What happened? - Not yet.
- 무슨 일이에요? - 아직 아님.
I think we're almost done.
거의 다 끝난 것 같아요.
We're still waiting.
우리는 아직 기다리고 있어요.
Let's check the bodies first.
먼저 시체를 확인해 볼까요?
What do you mean?
무슨 뜻이에요?
Seven. Eleven.
일곱. 열하나.
What? Eighteen people?
무엇? 18명?
- What? - That crazy jerk.
- 무엇? - 그 미친 놈.
Killed seven after breaking and entering a house?
집에 침입해 침입해 7명을 살해했다고?
Abducted and killed 11 women?
여성 11명을 납치해 살해했다?
Could he be the same guy?
그 사람도 같은 사람이 아닐까?
If he changed the MO, then it's possible.
MO를 변경했다면 가능합니다.
MO? Are you talking about the method of his crime?
미주리? 그의 범죄 수법을 말씀하시는 건가요?
You're right.
당신 말이 맞아요.
If he wanted to feel something stronger,
뭔가 좀 더 강한 느낌을 주고 싶다면,
there's a good chance that his MO could change.
그의 MO가 바뀔 가능성이 높습니다.
Do you think he's the culprit for all those cases?
그 사람이 이 모든 사건의 범인이라고 생각하시나요?
I doubt it.
나는 그것을 의심한다.
No, we can't come to any conclusion right now.
아니요, 지금 당장은 어떤 결론도 내릴 수 없습니다.
Let's check everything one after the other.
모든 것을 차례로 확인해 봅시다.
Wait.
기다리다.
It doesn't matter if he's the same guy or not.
그 사람이 같은 사람인지 아닌지는 중요하지 않습니다.
If what he said is true, this is a serious situation.
만약 그의 말이 사실이라면 이는 심각한 상황이다.
Make sure you keep this highly confidential. Understood?
이 내용을 기밀로 유지하십시오. 이해했다?
And you should go with Forensics.
그리고 법의학을 이용해야 합니다.
I'll go now.
나는 지금 갈 것이다.
Find out if he really buried those women.
그가 정말로 그 여자들을 묻었는지 알아보세요.
Okay.
좋아요.
- Man. - How can he do this?
- 남성. - 어떻게 이런 일을 할 수 있지?
How is this possible?
이것이 어떻게 가능합니까?
Why? What's wrong?
왜? 무슨 일이야?
- What's with him? - What's wrong?
- 그 사람은 뭐죠? - 무슨 일이야?
Hey, Gu Young Chun!
안녕하세요, 구영춘님!
Gu Young Chun, wake up!
구영춘아 일어나라!
- What's with him? - What?
- 그 사람은 뭐죠? - 무엇?
- Gu Young Chun. - His head.
- 구영춘. - 머리요.
- Tilt his head. - Give me a pen.
- 고개를 기울입니다. - 펜 좀 주세요.
What's with this jerk?
이 멍청이는 뭐죠?
Man.
남성.
Shouldn't we call an ambulance?
구급차를 불러야 하지 않나요?
Let's call one if he doesn't calm down in five minutes.
5분 안에 그 사람이 진정하지 않으면 전화하자.
What did you do?
당신은 무엇을 했나요?
I didn't do anything.
나는 아무것도 하지 않았다.
Wake up! Gu Young Chun!
깨우다! 구영춘!
Get up. Hey.
일어나세요. 여기요.
(Police)
(경찰)
(Seoul Metropolitan Police Agency)
(서울지방경찰청)
Do you have epilepsy?
간질이 있습니까?
You still have to go to the scene.
아직 현장에 가봐야 합니다.
We're ready.
우리는 준비되었습니다.
Can you let me...
허락해 주실 수 있나요...
breathe in fresh air one last time?
마지막으로 신선한 공기를 마시시겠습니까?
Put the cuffs on him.
그에게 수갑을 채워주세요.
I want to use the toilet.
화장실을 사용하고 싶어요.
Gosh. Do you think this is a hotel?
이런. 여기가 호텔인 것 같나요?
(Gentle, Trustworthy Seoul Police)
(부드럽고 믿음직한 서울경찰)
Guard the entrance.
입구를 지키세요.
(Men's room)
(남자화장실)
(Keep your uniform neat.)
(유니폼을 깔끔하게 유지하세요.)
(Take a step forward.)
(한 걸음 앞으로 나아갑니다.)
Hey! Catch him!
이봐! 그를 잡아라!
Take that. And...
가져가세요. 그리고...
Hey! Catch Gu Young Chun!
이봐! 구영춘을 잡아라!
Hurry! Catch Gu Young Chun!
서두르다! 구영춘을 잡아라!
Gu Young Chun!
구영춘!
Hey! Stop him!
여기요! 그만둬!
Gu Young Chun! Stop!
구영춘! 멈추다!
Go! Hurry up!
가다! 서둘러요!
Catch him!
그를 잡아라!
Catch that jerk.
그 멍청이를 잡아라.
Where did he go?
그는 어디로 갔습니까?
I'll go that way.
나는 그쪽으로 갈 것이다.
If we lose this guy, we'll be in big trouble.
이 사람을 잃으면 우리는 큰 어려움을 겪게 될 것입니다.
Give out the wanted posters. And locate him as soon as possible.
원하는 포스터를 나눠주세요. 그리고 가능한 한 빨리 그를 찾아보세요.
We must be discreet for now.
지금은 신중해야 합니다.
So let's say he committed theft.
그럼 그가 절도를 저질렀다고 가정해 봅시다.
Yes. Let's do that. I assigned resources for you.
예. 그렇게 해보자. 내가 당신을 위해 자원을 할당했습니다.
Focus on searching subway stations, train stations, bus terminals,
지하철역, 기차역, 버스터미널 검색에 집중하세요.
and any easy access points to run away.
도망칠 수 있는 쉬운 접근 지점도 있습니다.
- Yes, sir. - Okay. Go on. Now!
- 네, 선생님. - 좋아요. 계속하세요. 지금!
- Hurry up. - Okay.
- 서둘러요. - 좋아요.
I'm sending them out now.
지금 보내고 있어요.
Get the posters. Go to restaurants, motels, saunas,
포스터를 받으세요. 레스토랑, 모텔, 사우나에 가보세요.
and coffee shops. Just put them up everywhere.
그리고 커피숍. 그냥 아무데나 올려두세요.
So every citizen in Seoul can recognize this jerk's face.
그러니 서울시민이라면 누구나 이 멍청이의 얼굴을 알아볼 수 있을 것이다.
- Got it? - Yes, sir.
- 알았어요? - 네, 선생님.
Let me emphasize again. This is an emergency!
다시 한번 강조하겠습니다. 긴급 상황입니다!
If we don't catch him, we'll be humiliated!
그 사람을 잡지 못하면 우리는 망신을 당할 거예요!
- Got it? - Yes, sir.
- 알았어요? - 네, 선생님.
Run. Go out now!
달리다. 지금 나가세요!
- Go. - Go!
- 가다. - 가다!
- Come on. - I'm sorry.
- 어서 해봐요. - 죄송합니다.
(New Star Motel)
(뉴스타모텔)
We're from the police. Did you have a customer who looked like this?
우리는 경찰 출신이에요. 이런 고객이 있었나요?
- No. - Call us if you do.
- 아니요. - 그럴 경우 전화하세요.
Sure.
확신하는.
(The epilogue will air shortly.)
(에필로그는 곧 방송됩니다.)
(Through the Darkness, Part 2)
(어둠을 뚫고 2부)
I know today was a busy day.
오늘은 바쁜 날이었다는 걸 알아요.
You don't need to prepare a birthday meal for me.
당신은 나를 위해 생일 식사를 준비할 필요가 없습니다.
What are you talking about? I want to.
무슨 얘기를 하는 건가요? 나는 원한다.
It wasn't much of work.
별로 일이 ​​아니었어요.
To me, your birthday is as important as your dad's memorial day.
나에게 있어 너의 생일은 너의 아버지의 현충일만큼 중요하다.
Happy birthday.
생일 축하해요.
It must've been difficult to raise me alone.
저 혼자 키우시느라 많이 힘드셨을 텐데요.
So thank you.
감사합니다.
No, I should thank you.
아니요, 감사해야 합니다.
I wouldn't have been able to get through it without you.
당신이 없었다면 나는 그것을 이겨낼 수 없었을 것입니다.
I am proud...
자랑스럽다...
of you...
너...
because you have become a cop who can...
당신은 경찰이 되었기 때문에...
look into people's hearts better than anyone.
누구보다 사람의 마음을 잘 들여다보세요.
And I believe in you too.
그리고 나도 당신을 믿습니다.
You know that, right?
그거 알지?
Yes.
예.
Good morning.
좋은 아침이에요.
You're here.
당신은 여기 있습니다.
In 1, 2, 3, 4.
1, 2, 3, 4에서.
- Happy birthday to you - Happy birthday to you
- 생일 축하해 - 생일 축하해
- Happy birthday, dear Ha Young - Happy birthday, dear Ha Young
- 사랑하는 하영아 생일 축하해 - 사랑하는 하영아 생일 축하해
Gosh. This is so delicious.
이런. 정말 맛있어요.
- Dig in. - Hey.
- 파헤쳐 보세요. - 안녕.
Your mother is an excellent cook.
당신의 어머니는 훌륭한 요리사입니다.
Gosh, it's just some food.
맙소사, 이건 그냥 음식이에요.
We're feasting thanks to you.
우리는 당신 덕분에 잔치를 벌이고 있습니다.
This chocolate looks great.
이 초콜릿 정말 좋아 보이는데요.
- Well... - That's expensive.
- 음... - 비싸군요.
It was 35 dollars.
35달러였어요.
I like this. It's gotten so small.
나는 이것을 좋아한다. 너무 작아졌습니다.
You don't need tapes now. Just charge that.
이제 테이프는 필요하지 않습니다. 그냥 청구하세요.
- Really? - Can you hear it?
- 정말? - 들리나요?
Hello. Check. This is great.
안녕하세요. 확인하다. 이것은 훌륭합니다.
We got it. It's the hill in Nojin-dong.
우리는 그것을 얻었다. 노진동 언덕이에요.
- Right here! I found it. - Here too!
- 바로 여기요! 나는 그것을 찾았다. - 여기도요!
Here too!
여기도!
Darn...
젠장...
How's Captain Yoon?
윤 선장은 잘 지내요?
Did you even help her, Song Ha Young?
송하영씨도 도와주셨나요?
Why me?
왜 나야?
Why did you pick me for a position like this?
왜 나를 이런 자리에 뽑았나요?
To get what I want, I must fully understand my target.
내가 원하는 것을 얻으려면 목표를 완전히 이해해야 합니다.
Song Ha Young, what are you doing? Are you going?
송하영, 뭐해요? 갈 건가요?
To do that, I must become Gu Young Chun now.
그러기 위해서는 지금 구영춘이 되어야 한다.
I am you now.
나는 지금 당신이다.
(Tomorrow at 10pm)
(내일 오후 10시)